CURRICULUM VITAE

PERSONAL INFORMATION

BATEKA MPUTU Plandi



56, Mahenge, Ndendere, Bukavu, Democratic Republic of Congo

+243970626027 | +243891213801

plandimputu@gmail.com

Skype: plandi mputu

Sex Male | Date of birth 7th /December/1996 | Nationality Congolese (Democratic Republic of Congo)

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am an independent researcher, statistician and agronomist specializing in fruit, market gardening, coffee farming, fish farming and plant disease management. I carried out two studies, first on the management of weeds due to the seedling densities and second in the manufacture of biopesticides based on plant extracts. I participated in the performance evaluation studies of the Food security project of Consortium Mercy Corps and World Vision International in Kalehe, South-Kivu in Democratic Republic of Congo.

WORK EXPERIENCE

(From 01 June 2021 – 24 September 2021)

Program assistant officer

ACTED (Agency for Technical Cooperation and Development), South-Kivu Province / D.R. Congo.

- Planning activities
- Rapid Multisectorial Assessment
- Vulnerability survey of target population
- Food and shelter assistance

Sector: EMERGENCY PROJECT

(From 28th February 2019 – to date)

Advocacy and program officer

YPARD (Young Professional for Agriculture and Development) at Bukavu, 236 Avenue Patrice Emery Lumumba / South-Kivu Province / D.R. Congo, <u>yparddrcsk@gmail.com</u>.

- Planning and validation of activities
- Projects editing and evaluation
- Technical assistance in fish farming
- Paternship and funding research

Sector: AGRICULTURE AND SUSTAINABLE DEVELOPMENT

(From 01st Oct 2017 – 30th Nov 2020)

Agronomist/Technical advisor

REBUILD WOMEN HOPE COOPÉRATIVE at Bukavu, 04 Avenue Kabare/ South-Kivu Province / D.R. Congo, <u>rebuildw.h.o@gmail.com</u>

- Train rural population on conservation of the varietal gene of coffee and vegetable crops
- Agriculture extension of good practices to fight erosion and to restore soil fertility
- Seed conservation
- Biological control of crop diseases

Sector: AGRICULTURE AND SOCIO-ECONOMIC DEVELOPMENT

Curriculum Vitae

(From 26th Sept 2020 – 20th Jan 2021)

Technical coordinator

RECABIO (Réseau Congolais d'agriculture biologique) at Bukavu, 100 Avenue de la Montagne/ South-Kivu Province / D.R. Congo, <u>contact@recabio.org</u>

- Coordinate biological control activities against plant and animal disease with locally available resources
- Promote organic agricultural products in the local and international market.
- Help raise awareness of the danger caused by conventional pesticides

Sector: ORGANIC FARMING

(From 8th March 2021 – 30th March 2021)

Field investigator

(From 17th Nov 2020 – 24th Nov 2020)

Consortium Mercy Corps and World Vision International at Kalehe / South-Kivu Province / D.R. Congo

(From 1st Sept 2020 – 30th Sept 2020)

 Close and permanent monitoring of food distribution activities, farming tools and training in resilient agricultural techniques

(From 3rd March 2020 – 28th March 2020)

 Participation in the design of tools for collecting and analysing periodic data in the implementation of the food security project.

(From 20th Aug 2019 – 21st Sept 2019)

 ${\color{red} \bullet}$ Sensibilization of communities on their rights, standards of services to be excepte.

Sector: FOOD SECURITY

(From 26th Dec 2020 – 9th Jan 2021

Field investigator

IITA (International Institute of Tropical Agriculture / South-Kivu Province / D.R. Congo

- Assessment of the activities (farming, trading, etc) of the entrepreneurial potential of the youth of South Kivu Province.
- Assessment of agribusiness desirability among South Kivu youth in East of DR Congo.

Sector: AGRICULTURE AND ENTREPRENEURSHIP

(From 11th Jan 2021 – 19th Jan 2021)

Database management consultant

EDC (Education Development Center) at Bukavu, 19 Avenue Fizi / South-Kivu Province / D.R. Congo.

- Statistical analysis
- Survey

Sector: EDUCATION

(From Sept 2017 - Dec 2017)

Technical Manager

Plant and animal breeding Research Circle of Université Évangélique en Afrique at Bukavu, Panzi / South-Kivu Province / D.R. Congo

- Vegetable crops production
- Market garden products sale and distribution
- Agroforestry and other climate smart agriculture practices on hill of South Kivu Province

CURRICULUM VITAE

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

[from Oct, 24, 2017 – Oct, 30, 2019] Bachelor's degree

Université Evangélique en Afrique (Adresse: Q. Panzi, PO Box 3323)

Bukavu (Democratic Republic of Congo)

E-mail: ueabukavu@yahoo.fr Website: www.uea.ac.cd Call number: +243993084623

[from Sept, 15, 2014 – Oct, 24, 2017] Undergraduate degree

Université Evangélique en Afrique (Adresse: Q. Panzi, PO Box 3323)

Bukavu (Democratic Republic of Congo)

E-mail: ueabukavu@yahoo.fr Website: www.uea.ac.cd Call number: +243993084623

[from 15/09/2008 to 31/07/2014]

High school degree

Bwindi High School (Adresse: Q. Bagira) Bukavu (Democratic Republic of Congo)

E-mail: davidbyabene@yahoo.fr Website: www.institutbwindi.org Call number: +243998823959

PERSONAL SKILLS

Mother tongue(s)

French

Other language(s)

UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
B2	B1	B1	B1	B1
C1	C1	C1	C1	C1

English Swahili

Levels: A1/A2: Basic user - B1/B2: Independent user - C1/C2 Proficient user

Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

_				
D	idital	S	ΚII	IS

SELF-ASSESSMENT							
STATA	Arcgis	R software	Microsoft office	ODK, KOBO collect, Commcare			
INDEPENDENT USER	INDEPENDENT USER	BASIC USER	PROFICIENT USER	PROFICIENT USER			

Levels: Basic user - Independent user - Proficient user

Digital competences

Driving licence

A, B, C



ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Projects

- Mini rice mill for the processing of paddy rice in the Ruzizi plain in South-Kivu Province, Democratic Republic of Congo, (2021 – to date).
- Arabica Coffee milling in Idjwi territory with Rebuild Women hope Cooperative in South-Kivu Province, Democratic Republic of Congo, (2017 – to date).
- In vitro evaluation of the antifungal effects of plant extracts (Lantana camara, Tephrosia vogelii and Tithonia diversifolia) against Uromyces appendiculatus, the causative agent of bean rust isolated in the Karhongo group in Walungu territory, Democratic Republic of Congo, (2018 2019).
- The effects of seeding densities in maize cultivation on its yield and on the abundance of kashusha weeds in Kabare territory, Democratic Republic of Congo, (2016 – 2017).

REFERENCES

- Mme Sifa KISONGA: Program assistant of 21_EKU Emergency project at ACTED South Kivu / D.R. Congo. Tel: +243822927740.
- Mr. Damien MUHERYA: Monitoring and evaluation coordinator of the Food Security Project ENYANYA Program at World Vision International/ South Kivu / D.R. Congo. Tel: +243979666747.
 E-mail: damien muherya@wvi.org
- Mme. Marceline BUDZA: CEO of Rebuild Women Hope Cooperative / South Kivu / D. R. Congo. Tel: +243998748656. E-mail: marcelinebudza@gmail.com
- Mr. Landry RUBONEKA: YPARD Coordinator / South Kivu / D.R. Congo. Tel: +243997500085.
 E-mail: Kash.sojede@gmail.com